Preliminary Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. New York Office. Records, 1978-2000 and undated RL.10151
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company. New York Office. records
1978-2000 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company. New York Office
RL.10151
10.7 Linear Feet
491 Items
Access Restrictions
Collection is restricted.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. There may be a 48-hour delay in obtaining these materials.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The J. Walter Thompson Company. New York Office. Records were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2001.
Historical Note
The J. Walter Thompson Company was founded in New York, N.Y., in 1864, and is one of the world's largest advertising agencies.
Collection Overview
Collection (02-197) contains primarily presentations and reports in videotape and paper format made to and at World Partner Council meetings (1996-1997). Also includes Andy Fenning's files of reports and manuals in paper, video, slide, and digital format prepared for or received at management meetings, a "Transformation" seminar (1997), and other speeches and presentations. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising, and Marketing History.
The addition (02-194) consists of material gathered from office of Andy Fenning upon his departure from JWT, but representing the work of many people and JWT offices. Contains material related to MindShare (the media collaboration between JWT and the Ogilvy and Mather agency), and information and examples from the rollout and early days of the Thompson Total Branding approach. Comprises primarily an assortment of videotapes, 1978-2000, including showreels, historical reels, commercial spots, interviews, meetings, and other segments. Also includes a small number of files containing speeches, reports, presentations, and other materials.
Advertising agencies -- United States -- History; Advertising agencies -- United States; Management; Business presentations; Advertising agencies; Slides (photographs); Machine-readable records; Marketing; Videocassettes; Speeches; Manuals (instructional materials); John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History; J. Walter Thompson Company. New York Office; J. Walter Thompson Company; Ogilvy & Mather; J. Walter Thompson Company. New York Office; J. Walter Thompson Company -- History; Fenning, Andy
- Accessions 2002-0197 and 2002-0194
  Conditions Governing Access note
  Restricted: Unpublished materials less than 15 years old are closed to non-JWT researchers.
  - Contents of Box 1: (Box 1)
    - World Partners Council, Typescript and Video Presentations, 1996-1997 (Box 1)
  - Contents of Box 2: (Box 2)
    - World Partners Council, Typescript and Video Presentations, 1996-1997 (Box 2)
  - Contents of Box 3: (Box 3)
    - World Partners Council, Typescript and Video Presentations, 1996-1997 (Box 3)
  - Contents of Box 4: (Box 4)
    - World Partners Council, Typescript and Video Presentations, 1996-1997 (Box 4)
  - Contents of Box 5: (Box 5)
    - World Partners Council, Typescript and Video Presentations, 1996-1997 (Box 5)
  - Contents of Box 6: (Box 6)
    - World Partners Council, Typescript and Video Presentations, 1996-1997 (Box 6)
  - Contents of Box 7: (Box 7)
    - World Partners Council, Typescript and Video Presentations, 1996-1997 (Box 7)
  - Contents of Box 8: (Box 8)
    - Andy Fenning Files, Manuals and Reports, 1995-2000 (Box 8)
  - Contents of Box 9: (Box 9)
    - Andy Fenning Files, Manuals and Reports, 1995-2000 (Box 9)
  - Contents of Box 10: (Box 10)
    - Andy Fenning Files, Manuals and Reports, including from Latin America and Portugal, 1995-2000 (Box 10)
  - Contents of Box 11: (Box 11)
    - Andy Fenning Files, Manuals and Reports, including videotape on Transformation (1997), 1995-2000 (Box 11)
  - Contents of Box 12: (Box 12)
    - World Partners Council, Oversize Materials, 1996-1997 (Box 12)
    - Mindshare binder (Box 12)
  - Contents of Box 13: (Box 13)
    - Thompson Total Branding strategy files, presentations, speeches, 1995-1997 (Box 13)
    - Ford Truck slide presentation (Box 13)
  - Contents of Box 14: (Box 14)
    - Miscellaneous commercial spots, presentations (6 VHS tapes), 1993-1997 (Box 14)
  - Contents of Box 15: (Box 15)
    - Miscellaneous creative (6 VHS tapes) (Box 15)
  - Contents of Box 16: (Box 16)
    - Miscellaneous creative, show reels, commercials (6 VHS tapes), 1978-1999 (Box 16)
  - Contents of Box 17: (Box 17)
    - Miscellaneous show reels, interviews, commercials (9 VHS tapes), 1992-2000 (Box 17)
  - Contents of Box 18: (Box 18)
    - Miscellaneous meetings, show reels, interviews, commercials, etc. (14 VHS tapes) (Box 18)
    - 1 audiocasette, "Qwest" (Box 18)